Alexander Melocco

alexjmelocco@gmail.com • 0414 109 645

Projects Portfolio/GitHub link: https://alexmelocco.github.io/alexmelocco/

Profile

Motivated and dedicated university student with a passion for personal growth and a proven history of dedication to all facets of work. Pursuing a Bachelor of Software Engineering (Honors) at UNSW, I possess a diverse background in professional, technical and academic endeavors, including being honored with the Premier's Award for all around excellence.

Worked as a backend engineer for a startup Tutor Match, developing a hybrid content-based filtering search algorithm allowing extreme personalization for parents and tutor pairing. Further employed at Talent 100 as a mentor and teacher, gaining valuable experience in fostering collaborative relationships, demonstrating my aptitude in leadership. I also dedicate my time to social impact within the community with involvements in volunteering and Enactus seeing me compete Melbourne's 2023 and 2024 national social impact competition. I am excited to hopefully both challenge and apply my skills and knowledge within all my future commitments.

Technical Skills _____

- Python
- Java
- C++/C.

JavaScript

- CSS/HTML
- Socket Programming Web Development.
- Machine learning/AI
- Collaborative work experience (Gitlab, GitHub) MS applications
- Rust

Professional Experience

• **Tutor Match** Oct 2023 – Mar 2024

Backend software engineer at Tutor Match, a startup company aimed towards improving and providing free services to connect students and tutors. Designed and deployed hybrid content-based filtering search algorithm to improve and personalize student, tutor matches. Also responsible for backend architecture development. (tutormatch.com.au)

• **Talent 100** May 2022 – Current

Academic tutor and mentor for Talent 100

Enactus UNSW Jan 2023 – Current

Events director for management, synthesis and hosting events for UNSW Enactus which is a society with a primary focus on entrepreneurial social impact and making positive worldwide change through real projects.

• UNSW Microfinance Consulting Group January 2022 – December 2022

Responsible for event's planning, synthesis, and execution with the goal of helping other students enter the realm of consulting.

• Lime Seven January 2022 – April 2022

Sales consultant at Lime Seven which is a marketing and sales company.

• Australian Venue Co / Bungalow 8 April 2022 – November 2022

Bartender and beverage attendant

• Art of Smart Education May 2022 – December 2022

Academic tutor for Art of Smart

• Knox Grammar School App Developer 2020 – 2021

Responsible for interactive app development to allow cohort online coordination, and resource gatherer. Worked in the advertisement, marketing and event planning for student led operations.

Education & Qualifications

- UNSW (2022-current)
- Bachelor of Engineering (Honors)/Law
- 2023 Enactus National Social Impact Competition finalist
 - Knox Grammar School (2012-2021)
- 99.30 ATAR
- 2021 Silver Academic Award Knox
- 2021 Prefect Leader
- 2019 FED Debating Cup winner
- 2019 Kokoda Trail Participant
 - RSA/RCG Licensed

- Premier's award for all around excellence (2022)
- 2021 Silver Co-curricular Award Knox
- 2018 International Da Vinci Decathlon winner
- Bronze Duke of Edinburgh award
- Company Medic for Knox Cadet Unit

References

• Jennifer Kim – Head of Academic at Talent 100

j.kim@talent-100.com.au

0432 608 855

• David Nguyen – Student Services Manager at Talent 100

d.nguyen@talent-100.com.au

0423 065 405

Additional Information

- Cultural Experience: Travel often, and challenge myself in various physical disciplines, including embarking on Kokoda Trail in Papua New Guinea, and touring Europe for a Da Vinci Decathlon Competition
- Social impact and volunteering: Proud advocate for volunteering and championing projects that directly affect social progression. National Enactus Social Impact competition saw me go to Melbourne to compete is presenting the most socially transformative plans. Actively volunteer within my community and work within non-profit teams that work to develop biodegradable prosthetics (Enactus Prockets). Also involved in Tech4Impact which is a collaboration with the African STEM Education Initiative that focuses on lack of Stem education in Uganda.
- **Software Projects**: Strong passion for projects. My current double major with law and software engineering comes from a genuine passion towards possible contribution to the modernization of law. Also passionate in self-development with projects such as Flower iris recognition.
- Personal interest: Avidly enjoy physical sports such as boxing and powerlifting. Also love reading.